Shuchi Brata Roy

Mobile: +8801780363359 | Email: royshuchibrata@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub

NID: 7374023492

Present Address: 175, Principle Khagendranath Chakraborty Road, Narayanganj-1400

Permanent Address: VILL: Kamalla, PO: Kamalla-3540, UP: Muradnagar, DIST: Cumilla



PROFILE SUMMARY

Dedicated and enthusiastic computer science student, actively pursuing career opportunities to apply my skills and abilities. Experienced in computer networking & proficient communicator in English. Passionate about developing my knowledge, enhance my expertise, and gain valuable experience & make a meaningful contribution to a future organization.

EDUCATION QUALIFICATION

American International University-Bangladesh (AIUB)

Bachelor of Science (B.Sc) in Computer Science & Engineering (CSE)

CGPA: 3.56 out of 4.00

Government Tolaram College, Narayanganj

Higher Secondary School Certificate (HSC)

GPA: 4.33 out of 5.00 (Science)

Narayanganj High School & College

Secondary School Certificate (SSC) GPA: 4.91 out of 5.00 (Science)

Narayanganj, Bangladesh

2019

8 Jan 2020 - 10 Jan 2024

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Narayanganj, Bangladesh

2017

WORK EXPERIENCE

System Support Engineer (NOC)

(April 2024 - Present)

Tirzok Private Limited

Key Responsibilities:

- ⇒ Managed critical infrastructures, including:
 - **Surokkha** (Corona Vaccination Infrastructure)
 - VaxEPI (Health Services Citizen Portal)
 - **BMET** (Bureau of Manpower, Employment and Training Portal)
 - **TGTDCL** (Titas Gas Infrastructure)
 - TBS (Tirzok BICC Solution), TCS (Tirzok Cloud Service)
- Monitored Linux server performance using Nagios and Grafana, ensuring system availability and reliability through proactive analysis.
- Performed basic server configuration to optimize functionality and maintain operational stability.
- Server maintenance, issue troubleshooting and take necessary action.
- Daily & Monthly infrastructure report generation
- Internship at Information & Communication Technology Division

(Sept 2023 - Dec 2023)

Citizens Bank PLC

Head Office: Chini Shilpa Bhaban-2, 76 Motijheel C/A, Dhaka-1000, Bangladesh

- During my internship, I gained knowledge of the essential LAN and WAN equipment used in a bank, including their basic configuration and installation, as well as monitoring banking services using Zabbix.
- Engaged with the procurement process of ICT equipments.

CERTIFICATES

Certificate on CyberOps Associate course (CISCO)

ARCED Foundation

Certificate on JAVA-based programming participation

Certificate on Ultimate IT Networking Fundamentals

Udemy

AIUB

Certificate on Introduction to Python

Udemy

Certificate on Fundamentals of Python Machine Learning

Udemy

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Operating Systems: Windows, Linux (Ubuntu).

IDE Tools: CodeBlocks, Visual Studio, VS Code, R Studio, Google Colab, Kaggle,

Emu8086, Arduino IDE.

Design Software: Canva, Adobe.

Simulation Software: NI Multisim, Proteus, MATLAB, Simulink, Selenium IDE. **Programming Language:** C++, Java, C#, HTML, CSS, PHP, JavaScript, Python, R

Networking Tools: Security Onion, Cisco Packet Tracer.

Database: MySQL, Oracle.

OTHER EXPERIENCES

Thesis - Implemented Lung Cancer Detection using a Deep Learning approach. Utilizing Convolutional Neural Network (CNN) architecture, specifically the ResNet-50 & Support Vector Machine (SVM).

- Hands on experience of various course projects work and some engineering projects.
- Experience in conducting research on scholarly journals and conference papers, composting reports.

INTERESTS

- Cyber Security
- **Computer Networking**
- **Ethical Hacking**
- Information Technology

REFERENCES

KAZI MD. EHASANUZZAMAN

Executive Vice President & Head of ICT Division **Citizens Bank PLC**

Cell: 01711031433

Email: ehasan@citizensbankbd.com

DR. SHAMEEM AHMAD

Assistant Professor Electrical & Electronic Engineering

American International University-Bangladesh

Cell: 01767544806

Email: ahmad.shameem@aiub.edu

AKM SHAHRIAR

Senior Executive Officer Information & Communication Technology Division

Citizens Bank PLC

Cell: 01744366320

Email: akm.shahriar@citizensbankbd.com

GOURI SHANKAR ROY

Associate Professor Architecture Discipline **Khulna University** Cell: 01711347374

Email: gsroy@arch.ku.ac.bd